<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>B. Appendix on Operating Systems and C</title>
    <link>/appendix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in B. Appendix on Operating Systems and C</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <managingEditor>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;kuleuven.be&lt;/i&gt; (Wouter Groeneveld and Jo Vliegen)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;kuleuven.be&lt;/i&gt; (Wouter Groeneveld and Jo Vliegen)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="/appendix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Recommended reading</title>
      <link>/appendix/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;kuleuven.be&lt;/i&gt; (Wouter Groeneveld and Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>/appendix/reading/</guid>
      <description>Operating Systems Operating System Concepts  Another defining moment in the evolution of operating systems Small footprint operating systems, such as those driving the handheld devices that the baby dinosaurs are using on the cover, are just one of the cutting-edge applications you&amp;rsquo;ll find in Silberschatz, Galvin, and Gagne&amp;rsquo;s Operating System Concepts, Seventh Edition.
 Website: os-book.com
Programming in C The (Ansi) C Programming Language  This book is meant to help the reader learn how to program in C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Installation Instructions</title>
      <link>/appendix/installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;kuleuven.be&lt;/i&gt; (Wouter Groeneveld and Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>/appendix/installing/</guid>
      <description>The exercises for this course are to be done on a Linux machine. Because it is not expected that you reinstall your machines (or prepare them for dual boot) there is a virtual machine prepared for you 😃. This virtual machine runs Bodhi which is a lightweight linux distribution that is based on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS.
System Requirements The most crucial resource is disk space. The virtual machine image is 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat sheet</title>
      <link>/appendix/cheat_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;kuleuven.be&lt;/i&gt; (Wouter Groeneveld and Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>/appendix/cheat_sheet/</guid>
      <description>This cheat sheet summarises a set of commands, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to Google everything.
Linux commands Below is a brief list of Linux commands. Remember that you can get more info on a command by typing &amp;ldquo;command -h&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;man command&amp;rdquo;, or even google the manpage on Google.
Navigation    command goal     cd change directory   ls list (show content of current folder)    CLI tools    command goal     rm remove a file   touch create a file   grep search for content in a file   vi powerful editor with a steep learning curve (FYI: exiting is through: &amp;ldquo;:q!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>